Guide to the Pi Lambda Theth, Beta Omega chapter Records MS 053
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Pi Lambda Theta, Beta Omega Chapter Records
1972-1997
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Pi Lambda Theta. Beta Omega chapter
MS 053
4.5 Linear Feet, 4 boxes
The collection is made up of materials that Pi Lambda Theta members saved over the years that the Beta Omega chapter was in existence. The collection contains materials like membership pins and meeting iconography (candles, organizational symbols, music, letterhead, etc.), as well as, information regarding the activities of the chapter and meeting minutes.
Arrangement
Arranged into 2 series. Folders are arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
Pi Lambda Theta a national honor society of educators. PLT membership includes students and professionals who satisfy academic eligibility requirements, National Board-certified teachers and recipients PLT's awards. The Beta Omega chapter was formed in 1974 and the chapter closed in 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
Contains restricted information regarding members.
Custodial History
Donated by Pat Moriarity in 2010.
Scope and Contents
The collection is made up of materials that Pi Lambda Theta members saved over the years that the Beta Omega chapter was in existence and passed on reportedly from each successive chapter president.
Series I contains materials regarding the national office. These include directives, rules, brochures, and communiques that were generated by the national office.
Series II contains materials that pertain specifically to the Beta Omega chapter at WestConn. The series is divided into several subseries including: meetings, correspondence, financial, and membership. The objects subseries contains materials like membership pins and meeting iconography (candles, organizational symbols, letterhead, etc.). It also contains scrapbooks that contain images taken during meetings. In the first scrapbook there are images of Ruth Haas at an event marking the formation of the chapter. The meetings subseries gives the most information regarding the activities of the chapter and contains meeting minutes.
Women teachers.; Teachers -- Connecticut.; College students.; Western Connecticut State University; Vacha, Kathryn
- Series I: National Office Materials
  - Bylaws, etc, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Bylaws, rules, proceedures, and rules for membership
  - Election Materials, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Ballots, candidates inforomation, etc.
  - Forms, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Orders forms, memorabilia order forms, etc.
  - Memos, 1988-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
    National office and international office memos and communiques
  - Publications, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Pamphlets and newsletters
  - Directives and recommendations, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Lists of awards, information regardeing direct honors programs, and general information for chapters.
  - Northeast Region, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Northeast region-specific memos and directives.
- Series II: Beta Omega Chapter
  - Meetings
    - Minutes and meeting notes, 1987-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
      2 folders
    - Related publications, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Clippings, articles that relate to educational issues associated with meeting themes.
    - Executive committee minutes, 1987-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      2 composition books
  - Correspondence
    - Congratulatory letters, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Regarding the establishment of chapter and first members.
    - Miscellaneous, 1978-1996 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Most general correspondence from the national chapter.
  - Financial
    - Bills, receipts and invoices, 1989-1997 (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
      Contains bank statements, notes regarding dues, receipts and invoices from meetings.
  - Membership
    - Personal info, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Lists of members and notes, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Record Cards - applications, 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Objects
    - Scapbook, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Item 1)
      Images of Ruth Haas and the founding of the chapter.
    - Scrapbook, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Item 2)
    - Scrapbook (2), 1976-1990 (Box 2, Item 3-4)
    - Program planning kit, undated (Box 2, Item 5)
    - Welcome to Pi Lambda Theta packet, undated (Box 2, Item 6)
    - Pi Lambda Theta Chapter Publicity Kit, 1990s (Box 2, Item 7)
    - Checkbook, 1990s (Box 2, Item 8)
    - PO Box combination, 1990s (Box 2, Item 9)
    - Stationary, undated (Box 2, Item 10)
    - Membership certificates, undated (Box 2, Item 11)
    - Membership pins, undated (Box 2, Item 12)
    - Uncanelled stamps, undated (Box 2, Item 13)
    - Initiation sign-in sheets, undated (Box 2, Item 14)
    - "Song of Service" cassette and and sheet music, undated (Box 2, Item 15)
    - 2 meeting signs, undated (Box 2, Item 16)
    - Pi Lambda Theta tote bag, undated (Box 2, Item 17)
    - Ceremonial Objects, undated (Box 3, Item 1-4)
      Gavel, table cloth, candles, candle holders.
    - Iconography, undated (Item storageBox)
      Symbol of the Pi Lambda Theta for ceremonies.